Angel Rosario

New York, NY | arosario.us@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Medium | Portfolio

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Software engineer with hands-on experience utilizing React and Ruby on Rails. I have varied professional and personal experiences, including locally, internationally, and remotely. Those experiences have molded me into a go-getter and into someone that is good with time management, adaptable, and able to work equally well individually or as part of a team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, SQL, CSS, HTML, Postgres, Active Record, Heroku, REST, GitHub

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Around Town - GitHub | Demo

First individual full stack project. React frontend, Ruby on Rails backend. This is a general travel / local message board.

- Developed user account features with full CRUD and authentication.
- Utilized model-view-controller with custom routes.
- Dynamic location and weather fetching from an external API, via the backend. PostgreSQL is utilized.
- Designed with a combination of custom CSS, inline styling, and Semantic UI.

Hotel Mario - GitHub | Demo

Hotel management (PMS) system. React frontend, Ruby backend.

- Collaborated with a team of three on a project as an introduction to full stack development.
- Programmed for hotel staff (user) that allows for full CRUD actions. They can view available rooms, update a room's
 reservation status, view room information, and delete a room.
- Designed with a combination of inline styling and Semantic UI.

Reactions Journal - GitHub | Demo

Journal / note taking app. React frontend.

- Collaborated with a team of three on a frontend project.
- Developed with the idea of allowing the user to create and log their diary entries to a JSON database. Users can sort entries and update their contact information as well.
- Designed mainly via styled components.

EXPERIENCE

Aurora English School

Saitama, Japan

English Instructor / Manager

08/2018 - 09/2021

- Co-founded a new language school. Co-developed the curriculum and taught English lessons.
- Communicated with students and parents in order to tailor lessons based on their levels and specific learning goals.

Appen Remote

Social Media Evaluator

11/2015 - 11/2020

- Followed specified guidelines and self-managed time and workflow in order to evaluate internet-based content.
- Kept pace with specified number of tasks completed per hour under no external supervision.

 TaskRabbit
 New York, NY

 Tasker
 01/2015 - 03/2017

- Assisted clients in a variety of tasks, including moving help and deliveries.
- Achieved a <u>five star average rating</u> based on reliability, accuracy, patience, flexibility, thoughtfulness, politeness, and responsiveness.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

New York, NY
Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript programming bootcamp

04/2022

ruii Stack web Development, Ruby on Raiis and JavaScript programming bootcamp

New York, NY

Bachelor of Arts, Journalism

Baruch College

12/2010